Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
S-Superficial?
In other words, chilblains.
You were close to getting frostbite.
If you walk around in a blizzard for
a long time with an automail like that,
you'll get frostbite where it is connected to your body.
You also won't be able to move very well unless you change your oil.
Is that Buccaneer guy's automail made differently?
It's no good, Doc. I can't get this helmet off.
Hey! That's my head!
All automail here must be made to be flexible, lightweight, and resistant to cold.
So through trial and error, an automail made with duralumin, carbon fiber, nickel, and copper was developed.
I thought it was just made of iron.
No wonder I couldn't destroy it.
Hey Doc, you're not planning on spilling all the beans, are you?
Why, what's wrong?
He's a famous State Alchemist.
Are you sure he's real?
He has the silver pocketwatch.
A guy like this is of equal standing to a major?
If you're planning on staying up north for a while, you should switch to a cold climate automail.
Where does your automail mechanic work?
Rush Valley.
They knew a customer was heading up north and didn't even bother to tell you the dangers or offer a replacement?
Well... I didn't tell her that I was going to be up here.
If you don't want to die, you need to get it replaced;
even if it means your mechanic has to take a trip here.
Fine.
That'll be 100 cenz for the coffee.
What a cheap trick...
And this coffee tastes worse than the one at Eastern Headquarters.
Your fault for letting your guard down.
So? What did you come here to do with that normal automail of yours?
Coming along without even passing through Headquarters.
That's right!
We came here with a letter of introduction to see if Major General Armstrong could help us out,
but that general didn't even listen to me and was
blabbering on about how she'd pluck my antenna off...
Did you call, little brat?
"L-Little"...
What is it?
If you've got something to say, just say it.
M-My hair...
I look ridiculous...
Ice Queen
So... I hear you're on good terms with my little brother, Alex.
Is he doing well?
Yeah.
As muscular as always.
He's as cheerful as can be.
"Tch"?!
Nevermind that.
Moving right along, tell me why you came to see me without going through Headquarters first.
Don't forget to include why that armor is empty, as well.
It's actually... something I don't want a lot of people to know about.
You've got nothing to worry about.
Most of the people here have circumstances of their own.
It's not uncommon for us to have things we don't want others to hear, as well.
It's the kind of thing that could get me
court-martialed if people were to find out...
I've done things of that caliber, as well.
Brother, listen.
I don't think she'll forgive us unless we tell her something.
But Winry is practically a hostage.
I have an idea.
Let's leave out the part about the
Führer President and the Homunculi.
What are you whispering on about?!
I don't have all day!
Then I guess we can just tell her,
"We're on a journey to get our bodies back".
I see. So that's why you're looking for a girl who carries this cat around.
I get it now.
Then will you help us-
I get you are scatterbrains who act without thinking and end up adding fuel to flames because of your carelessness.
I don't want to keep fools like you in my castle.
Seriously... why don't the higher-ups at Central keep fools like you chained up?
Leave here at once!
...is what I'd like to say, but I'm highly interested in Eastern Alchemy.
You two are acquainted with that girl from Xing, right?
Yeah, I guess you could say that...
It's technology we don't have in this country.
I want it.
You can never have enough technology.
Especially in this land, where we frequently combat Drakma, a large nation.
Depending on how we apply it, Eastern Alchemy may become a useful combat tool for us.
Hang on!
Eastern Alchemy is especially versed in medicinal purposes.
Using that for war-
Did I give you permission to speak?
You're nothing but dogs that do nothing but bark within the borders of the country.
Don't you forget for a second that you fools are living in peace because there exist those who protect the borders.
I am in charge of protecting the northern border.
If the technique would be useful to my duty, then I'll take it. Whatever it may be.
Leave the search for the little girl to us.
I don't want you two out of the fortress.
And Major Miles.
Ma'am?
Give these two some work to do.
W-What?!
"If a man will not work, he shall not eat."
Can't argue with that...
They've got quite a rough history behind them.
Although they seem to be fairly experienced in combat, I now know that they're just brats on the inside.
Also...
It seems like they have some secrets they're not willing to share with us.
Hey, what are you going to make us do exactly?
The doctor said that a lot of people here have
circumstances of their own. Does that go for you, too?
So you ask us about every detail of our lives,
and now you're ignoring us? Talk about unfair!
Do you really want to know?
Red eyes?!
An Ishbalan?!
Why...
I heard that all of the soldiers of Ishbalan descent were purged before the extermination...
I do have some Ishbalan blood in me.
However, my grandmother, my father, and my wife do not.
The colors of my skin and eyes came from my grandfather.
Amestrian...
You sure had your way with
the land of my ancestors, didn't you?
You Ishbalans burned down my hometown, too, and even killed my friend's parents.
Cut it out, Brother!
Sorry about that.
You're actually the first one who talked back after I said that.
You were testing me, weren't you?
I apologize.
It's just that people view me with pity after that civil war.
To be honest, I was getting sick of it.
But you were different.
Well, I've met Ishbalans who wanted to kill me, ones who tried to kidnap me, and others I've made peace with.
So I've been through a lot.
And besides, I believe it's possible for individuals to be able to talk as equals without having to worry about race.
Were you enlisted in the military during the extermination, Major Miles?
Yeah.
I served as assistant to Major General Armstrong then, too.
The extermination began as soon as I was stationed here,
and all of my Ishbalan relatives, beginning with my grandfather, were killed in the East.
My life was saved due to my narrowly missing the requirements of the purge statute.
Did you not come to despise the military?
You don't hesitate to ask anything, do you?
I hate being ignorant.
I apologize if I offended you in any way.
A State Alchemist being ignorant, huh...
I did despise what the military did.
And at the same time, I had doubts about the
Major General for keeping me as her assistant.
By having someone like me, a person with Ishbalan blood around, it could cause trouble with the soldiers here.
Yet, the Major General didn't exile me,
so I turned on her in anger and demanded answers.
Briggs shall not fall, no matter what happens.
Every soldier here must be strong and flexible, fulfilling my every command.
They must make up a sturdy army that would keep calm under all circumstances.
In other words, there's no time for racism.
Because the blood of many races runs through your veins,
you view this country from many angles and with many values.
Because I was born and raised an Amestrian, I need someone like you by my side for me to be able to stand at the top.
Follow my command without complaint, Miles!
Perfectly logical.
Not to mention that her words carried no deception.
I proceeded to ask her, "Even then, what if the Ishbalan in me couldn't forgive the army and took over my mind?"
How do you think she responded to that?
Very well. Bring it on.
I'll accept a duel from you at any time, as a representative of the army.
Is what she said.
What an evil woman.
It should be easy saying that with a battalion at her back.
No, I'm fairly certain...
I'll slice you up in a one-on-one duel!
...her eyes were saying that.
Are you aware of the universal law at this base?
"Survival of the fittest", was it?
That's right.
Ones without power will die,
and ones with power will survive.
This is always true, under any circumstances.
It's very simple.
There are no underlings, bosses, and no distinctions between race, ethnicities, and gender.
There's a good example of the survival of the fittest concept.
You lived through it because you had good luck.
Looks like the guys who were supposed to be removing the icicles loafed on the job.
It's your job now.
I'll tell one of my men to give you
a tour of the inside once you finish.
I can't reach that high!
Huh? Don't tell me...
Warrant Officer Falman!
Elric Brothers!
What are you doing here?
Speak for yourself! I thought you were getting transferred to Northern Headquarters!
I was actually sent here from Northern Headquarters.
You were promoted to Second Lieutenant!
Yeah.
Oh. Congratulations on your promot-
But why are you in charge of the icicles?
If you're here working the duties of the enlisted...
Looks like that'll be your last promotion.
Shut up!
This is the development lair.
Wow, what's that?
They're developing weapons using the best technology in the country under orders from Major General Armstrong.
Even automails for combat?
Yes.
Let me show you something else.
This is the lowest level of Briggs.
It's really warm down here.
Totally different from how it is up at the top.
The lifeline of the fortress is gathered here.
Even if the top of the fortress is attacked,
the central part underground will remain unscathed.
Out of my way!
Don't be milling around!
Sorry.
Hey Bobby, this way!
It's this pipe.
This sound...
It's coming from underground.
What?!
It sounds like... someone's digging.
Don't tell me the Drakmans are building
an underground passage beneath the fortress?!
It's really close!
What a drag...
Really, what a drag...
It's such a drag, I could die.
But dying is also a drag.
Solf J. Kimblee?
He was badly injured on a freight train on the way here and was hospitalized at the foot of the mountain.
He requests that Briggs supports him.
Wasn't the Crimson Alchemist serving in jail?
Apparently, he was discharged.
Under orders from the Führer President.
I don't like the sound of that.
What's the matter?!
Intruders, ma'am! From underground!
What?!
Homunculus!
Dammit!
So they knew we came up here to search for ways to fight against the Homunculi?!
Don't fall asleep!!!
What?
Well, you know.
You heard about us from your Father at Central, right?
Y-Yeah.
We just came here to search for ways to get our bodies back...
Who... are you guys?
I... have to dig.
What a drag...
Such a drag...
Wait, could it be that he...
Yeah. Maybe neither Father nor the
Führer President have told him about us yet.
You bastard! So you are  spies from Drakma!
We're not!
Then why are you speaking to the intruder like you're friends?!
We're not friends!
You can't trick me!
This is in the way.
We're not lying!
We're just...
There's... so much room here.
Where am I?
Do I not have to dig anymore?
Fire!
Bullets are ineffective?!
Where... am I?
This is bad! He's headed for the development lair!
After him!
Contact the men up there!
We need to go after him, too!
Right!
He's huge...
It's... warm in here...
Stay where you are!
Put out the fire.
Roger!
I know I hit him...
It's no use, Boss!
Bullets don't work against him!
What did you say?!
All noncombatants are to withdraw immediately.
Shut off the alarm, too.
Don't let Drakma know about this commotion.
I've brought it, Boss!
Has it been tested?
There's no need for that.
It's the proud of work of us developers!
Remove the fuse from the shell!
Aye, ma'am!
First shell, loaded!
Fire!
Bull's eye!
Oww...
It's a drag to feel pain, too...
Don't just sit there!
Load the next shell!
Fire!
Oww...
Oh yeah, I forgot about my job.
I have to dig.
It's no use, General!
He won't die no matter what!
Won't die?!
What do you mean?!
Why do you know so much about that thing?!
I-I...
I don't like dilly-dalliers!
Answer everything that you can  answer!
How do you know about that thing?!
Are you a spy from Drakma?!
No!
Then is that thing a spy?!
I don't think so.
Does that thing know you?!
Probably not.
What is  that thing?!
I can't answer.
Who is commanding him to act?!
I can't answer!
And why can't you answer?
Please try to realize...
This is my last question.
Do you two plan to ally yourselves with us?
I don't want to see the people here die.
Tell me what his body is made of.
I'm fairly certain his body structure and composition are identical to humans.
Identical to humans, huh...
Buccaneer, bring me some tank fuel.
I'm going to pour it on him.
Roger!
I'm telling you, it's useless!
Even if you light him on fire, he won't...
I've already gathered from the
previous attacks that he won't die.
In that case, I'll just shut off his bodily functions.
I'll let him have something far worse than flames.
I'll show you how we do things at Briggs.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
The bodies that clash against each other..
The shells that explode in the air...
The battle against the Homunculus threatening the North defense.
Will it be us who will win the battle? Or perhaps...
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
The Shape of This Country
Episode 35, The Shape of This Country.
All that stands in our way shall be annihilated.
That is the law of the North.